Do you love food?
你热爱美食吗？
Whether you’re a foodie or someone who just likes eating, there is so much to choose from.
无论你是美食家，还是仅仅喜欢美食的人，可供选择的食物都有很多。
We know that too much of the wrong kind of food can be bad for our health, but for some people having a food allergy means eating certain things can actually be harmful - and now, it seems, this is affecting more and more of us.
我们都知道，过量食用不健康的食物会损害健康，但对一些有食物过敏症的人来说，吃某些食物其实是有危害的——而且如今，受这个问题影响的人似乎越来越多。
An allergy is caused by the immune system fighting substances in the environment, known as allergens, that it should see as harmless.
过敏是免疫系统攻击环境中本应被视为无害物质（即过敏原）而引发的。
Food allergies can cause life-threatening reactions, which means people have to spend their lives following strict dietary restrictions and worrying about the ingredients of everything they consume.
食物过敏可能会引发危及生命的反应，这意味着患者一生都要遵守严格的饮食限制，还要时刻担心自己所吃的每一样东西的成分。
Allergy specialist Dr Adam Fox says “if you look back over, say, 30 or 40 years… there are much more allergic problems around now than there were.”
过敏专科医生亚当·福克斯博士表示：“回顾过去三四十年，不难发现现在的过敏问题比以往多得多。”
We often hear about people having allergies to dairy products and to peanuts.
我们经常听说有人对乳制品和花生过敏。
Last year a 15-year-old girl died after suffering a fatal allergic reaction from eating a baguette containing sesame seeds.
去年，一名15岁女孩因食用含有芝麻的法棍面包引发致命过敏反应而死亡。
This led to a call for better food-labelling laws.
这一事件引发了人们对完善食品标签法规的呼吁。
Research has found that this problem is particularly affecting children.
研究发现，这个问题对儿童的影响尤为明显。
More and more of them are having allergic reactions to certain foodstuffs.
越来越多的儿童会对某些食物产生过敏反应。
Writing for the BBC website, Dr Alexandra Santos from King's College London says “food allergy now affects about 7% of children in the UK and 9% of those in Australia, for example.
伦敦国王学院的亚历山德拉·桑托斯博士在为英国广播公司网站撰稿时表示：“例如，目前英国约有7%的儿童、澳大利亚约有9%的儿童患有食物过敏症。
Across Europe, 2% of adults have food allergies.”
在整个欧洲，有2%的成年人存在食物过敏问题。”
So what might be the cause?
那么，造成这种现象的原因可能是什么呢？
Dr Santos says the increase in allergies is not simply the effect of society becoming more aware of them and better at diagnosing them; it seems to be more environmental.
桑托斯博士表示，过敏症患者增多，不仅仅是因为社会对过敏的认知度提高、诊断水平有所进步，这一现象似乎更多与环境因素有关。
She says possible factors are “pollution, dietary changes and less exposure to microbes, which change how our immune systems respond.”
她指出，可能的诱因包括“污染、饮食变化以及接触微生物的机会减少，这些因素都会改变人体免疫系统的反应方式”。
She points out that it’s very common for migrants who move to another country to develop asthma and food allergies in their new location.
她还提到，移居他国的移民在新的生活地患上哮喘和食物过敏症，是十分常见的情况。
A lot of work is being done to try and find a cure, but that’s not easy.
目前，人们正在投入大量精力寻找治愈过敏的方法，但这并非易事。
So for now allergy sufferers must watch what they eat and they must rely on clear and accurate labelling.
因此，就现阶段而言，过敏患者必须格外留意自己的饮食，同时还要依赖清晰准确的食品标签。